Thiyanesh Kamaraj

Oracle PL\SQL Developer

Highly versatile developer application with 9+ years of experience in development of Banking applications with prowess in learning technology, knack to work in team to achieve concrete goals on a strict deadline. Strong skills include Oracle database and shell scripting.



ThiyaneshK@gmail.com



+91 9543345171



Chennai, India



linkedin.com/in/thiyaneshk

SKILLS & COMPETENCE

Oracle

PL\SQL

OAD

Shell

Perl

Sybase

Flexcube

B@NCS24

Jenkins

BitBucket

Јіга

Core banking Services

Agile

CICD

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Consultant

Virtusa Polaris

10/2018 - Present Citi Bank - Japan

Chennai, India

Chennai, India

Achievements/Tasks

- Developed database architectural strategies at modeling, design and implementation stages for migration of legacy Sybase database to Oracle database.
- Migration of MIS application from Sybase to Oracle in view to implement most secure and robust financial reporting application for Citi Bank - Japan.
- Gathered, defined and refined requirements, led project design and oversaw implementation.
- Determined areas for improvement and implemented processes which leveraged Oracle security features to alleviate problems.
- Automated EUC files into automated reports as value-adds to user, which reduced 1hr of human effort per day and reduced cost-to-company of \$200,000 per year
- Created common utils package for the application with custom functions and autonomous logging, which improved code reusability and code quality.
- Agile application development including constant feedback from clients and implementation of robust system.
- Created scripts in shell/Perl and processes for data loading, integration, maintenance, data quality check and other tools used for the implementation.

Application Developer

Oracle Financial Services Software

08/2016 - 10/2018 Flexcube Universal banking solution for middle-east and Asia pacific clients

Achievements/Tasks

- Customization of the application to the needs of the clients, which includes understanding the business requirement, feasibility study, implementation of the same by coding the same which includes creation of database objects like tables, triggers, views and packages, procedures, functions with the highest degree of coding standards.
- Catering needs of Flexcube universal banking applications to a range of clients in development and maintenance of clients in the Middle East and Asia Pacific.
- Reduction of EoD/EoM runtime over 20-30% by performance tuning on analyzing AWR/ADDM reports for faster application design and development.
- Involved in migrating Toplink to POJO, which improved the performance of the application considerably.
- Implemented system of tracking the bugs spotted in various clients and proactivily fixing the bugs in all the clients running the same version of Flexcube, which decreased number of issues raised clients and inturn improved customer satisfaction.

Thiyanesh Kamaraj

ACHIEVEMENTS

Migration of database from Sybase to Oracle with very tight deadline.

Hands on experience in TCS B@NCS and Oracle FLEXCUBE banking applications and its development.

Awarded PERL in Virtusa

INTERESTS

Traveling Cycling

Trekking

hiking

Volunteering

Tree plantation

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer HCL Technologies Ltd.

12/2014 - 08/2016

Staples Inc. Rewards system

. .

Tasks/Achievements

- Application development with all stages of System Development Life Cycle (SDLC). Applied Database Tuning and Optimization, Normalization under tight schedules of development and implementation.
- Development includes Tier upgrade/downgrade/association process where
 Customers are assigned to tiers according to sales made as per business rules.
- Automation of Scripts in Shell and Perl which replaced work of L1/L1.5 team in reports and Monitoring process. Further improved productivity with reduced cost to the company.
- Tuning the existing PL/SQL codes to run faster and perform better in a scaleble environment. Improved the performance of the critical daily sales process and reduced the run time by 30%.
- Created 6 value-adds worth \$105,000 which brought new business to the Company and have satisfied the customer as it improved productivity. Obtained high acclaims for the same.

Developer

C-Edge Tech. (A TCS - SBI Enterprise)

10/2012 - 12/2014

Chennai, India

Chennai, India

Core banking Service provider to financial institutions in India and abroad

Tasks/Achievements

- B@NCS Core banking implementation for over 25 Banks which contained over 850+ Banks in them. Worked in Client location which involved direct interaction with clients to obtain the requirement.
- Extensive experience in development of modules in PL\SQL, COBOL. Development of automation scripts using UNIX Shell and Perl to improve productivity and enhance the existing scripts.
- Headed a Team of 2-4 members as Team lead of Reports, GL and Deposit Modules. Develop tool to automatically send reports and files which failed to deliver over ftp. This process reduced work of L1.5 and improved the productivity and improved client's satisfaction with the available narrow band and obtain highest success rate of delivery in turn reduce the cost considerably.
- Developed PL\SQL codes to validate the data during migration, validate the interest/accrual given during migration according to the interest rates present in the system.
- Trained/Mentored a quality team and we enforced all quality process and obtained low defect outcome as much as 0.01 DTCR.

EDUCATION

B.Tech, Information TechnologyPallavan College of Engineering

04/2008 - 04/2012

Chennai, India, 7.61 CGPA